vooks.com 2019-12-19

# Privacy Policy — Vooks

### Privacy Policy

Effective date: May 6, 2019

Vooks, Inc ("us", "we", or "our") operates the www.vooks.com website and the Vooks mobile application (hereinafter referred to as the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, the terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions.

## Definitions

 **Service**

Service means the www.vooks.com website and the Vooks mobile application operated by Vooks, Inc

 **Personal Data**

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from that data (or from other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

 **Usage Data**

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

 **Cookies**

Cookies are small files stored on your device (computer or mobile device).

 **Data Controller**

Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.

 **Data Processors (or Service Providers)**

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

 **Data Subject (or User)**

Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

## Information Collection and Use

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### Types of Data Collected

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

·       Email address

·       First name and last name

·       Phone number

·       Address, State, Province, ZIP/Postal code, City

·       Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send or by contacting us.

We may also collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service or when you access the Service by or through a mobile device ("Usage Data").

This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

When you access the Service with a mobile device, this Usage Data may include information such as the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device unique ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browser you use, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and we hold certain information.

Cookies are files with a small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Other tracking technologies are also used such as beacons, tags and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyse our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

·       **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.

·       **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.

·       **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

## Use of Data

Vooks, Inc uses the collected data for various purposes not limited to the purposes listed below:

·       To provide and maintain our Service

·       To notify you about changes to our Service

·       To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so

·       To provide customer support

·       To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service

·       To monitor the usage of our Service

·       To detect, prevent and address technical issues

·       To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

## Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), Vooks, Inc legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.

Vooks, Inc may process your Personal Data because:

·       We need to perform a contract with you

·       You have given us permission to do so

·       The processing is in our legitimate interests and it is not overridden by your rights

·       For payment processing purposes

·       To comply with the law

## Retention of Data

Vooks, Inc will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

Vooks, Inc will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer periods.

## Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ from those of your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Vooks, Inc will take all the steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organisation or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## Disclosure of Data

### Business Transaction

If Vooks, Inc is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, Vooks, Inc may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### Legal Requirements

Vooks, Inc may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

·       To comply with a legal obligation

·       To protect and defend the rights or property of Vooks, Inc

·       To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service

·       To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public

·       To protect against legal liability

## Security of Data

The security of your data is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## Our Policy on "Do Not Track" Signals under the California Online Protection Act (CalOPPA)

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

## Your Data Protection Rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. Vooks, Inc aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete or limit the use of your Personal Data.

If you wish to be informed about what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.

In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

 **The right to access, update or delete the information we have on you.** Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.

 **The right of rectification.** You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.

 **The right to object.** You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.

 **The right of restriction.** You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.

 **The right to data portability.** You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.

 **The right to withdraw consent.** You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where Vooks, Inc relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

## Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), provide the Service on our behalf, perform Service-related services or assist us in analysing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyse the use of our Service.

 **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualise and personalise the ads of its own advertising network.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

### Payments

We may provide paid products and/or services within the Service. In that case, we use third-party services for payment processing (e.g. payment processors).

We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. These payment processors adhere to the standards set by PCI-DSS as managed by the PCI Security Standards Council, which is a joint effort of brands like Visa, MasterCard, American Express and Discover. PCI-DSS requirements help ensure the secure handling of payment information.

The payment processors we work with are:

 **Apple Store In-App Payments**

Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/>

**Google Play In-App Payments**

Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

**Stripe**

Their Privacy Policy can be viewed at <https://stripe.com/us/privacy>

## Links to Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

## Affiliations 

As an Amazon Associate I earn from qualifying purchases.

## Children's Privacy

Vooks is committed to protecting you and your family’s personal information. We want Vooks to be a safe and enjoyable environment for everyone. In this Privacy Policy, we’ll explain what we do with the information you give us and what we may collect from you as part of providing the Vooks service.

We comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, (COPPA) a U.S. law that governs the use and collection of information online from kids under 13. To learn more about COPPA, consult this website: <https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online>

By using the Vooks service via our websites or mobile apps we obtain your consent for our collection of certain information about the use of our service. This may included information about you and your children as parent or guardian in accordance with COPPA requirements.

If you submit any information relating to other people in connection with the our services, you represent that you have the authority to do so and permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Types of information we collect

We collect two basic types of information – personal information (as defined in this policy) and anonymous information (as defined in this policy) – and we may use personal and anonymous information to create a third type of information, aggregate information (also defined in this policy). For example, we collect:

\- Registration information you provide when you create an account, enter a promotion, or link your profile on a third-party site or platform with your registration account, such as your first name and surname, country of residence, gender, date of birth, email address, username, and password;

\- Transaction information you provide when you request information, contact Vooks support, or purchase a product or service from us, such as your postal address, telephone number, and payment information;

\- Information you provide in public forums on our sites and applications, such as your public posts;

\- Information sent either one-to-one or within a limited group using our message, chat, post, or similar functionality, where we are permitted by applicable law to collect this information;

\- Information we obtain from a third party, such as a site or platform provider, about use of our applications on third-party platforms or devices;

\- Location information, including location information provided by a mobile or other device interacting with one of our sites or applications (including through beacon technologies), or associated with your IP address, where we are permitted by law to process this information;

\- Activity information about your use, and the use by any person(s) you authorize through your account, of our sites and applications, such as the content you view or post, how often you use our services, and your preferences; and

\- Usage, viewing, technical, and device data when you visit our sites, use our applications on third-party sites or platforms, or open emails we send, including your browser or device type, unique device identifier, and IP address.

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

Our website will always have the most current privacy policy, and we will update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

·       By email: support@vooks.com

·       By visiting this page on our website: www.vooks.com

You can also write to us at: 

_Vooks_

2066 NW Irving St. Suite 4

Portland OR, 97209
